John Alden Mason Papers 1904-1967 Mss.B.M384
American Philosophical Society
John Alden Mason Papers
1904-1967
Mss.B.M384
American Philosophical Society
26.75 Linear feet
An archaeological anthropologist and linguist, John Alden Mason spent the majority of his career at the University Museum of the University of Pennsylvania. After receiving his undergraduate degree at Penn in 1907, Mason received a doctorate at Berkeley (1911) for his ethnographic work on the Salinan Indians of California, but his diverse interests in later years ran the gamut from Puerto Rican folklore to Piman languages and cultures (including Pima, Papago, Pima Bajo, Northern and Southern Tepehuan, and Tepecano), Mayan, Aztec, and Incan archaeology, and the languages of South American Indians. Mason was curator of the University Museum at Penn from 1926 until his retirement in 1958. The Mason Papers include both in-coming and outgoing correspondence, linguistic material, notes, and photographs relating to Mason's work in the southwestern U.S., northern Mexico, and South America. Centered on the years after Mason's return to Philadelphia in 1926, the collection covers all aspects of Mason's professional life, from reports on field work to answering casual questions referred to him through the University Museum to data and analyses on Piman and other languages. The collection also contains voluminous files relating to the Mason's editorship of the American Anthropologist (bulk: 1945-1948). Of special note are a series of class notes (1908-1910) kept by Mason for course work in ethnology, archaeology, and linguistics at the University of Pennsylvania under Edward Sapir and Frank Speck.
Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
Bibliography
The following works by and about Mason appear in the APS Library collections:
Kidder, Alfred, and Linton Satterthwaite, "John Alden Mason," Expedition 10 (1968), 2-3. Call no.: 507.73 P38bu
Satterthwaite, Linton, "John Alden Mason, 1885-1967" American Anthropologist 71 (1969), 871-879 Call. no.: 572.05 Am3
Mason, John Alden, The Ethnology of the Salinan Indians (Berkeley, 1912). Call no.: 378.794 C12pam.
Mason, John Alden, The Mutsun Dialect of Costanoan Based on the Vocabulary of De la Cuesta (Berkeley, 1916). Call no.: 378.794 C12pam.
Mason, John Alden, The Language of the Salinan Indians (Berkeley, 1918). Call no.: 378.794 C12pam.
Mason, John Alden, Archaeology of Santa Marta, Colombia: The Tairona Culture... Marshall Field archaeological expedition to Columbia, 1922-23 (Chicago, 1931). Call no.: 572.07 F45.
Mason, John Alden, "The Tepehuan and the other aborigines of the Mexican Sierra Madre Occidental" America Indigena 8 (1948) Call no.: 572.98 M38x.
Mason, John Alden, The Language of the Papago of Arizona (Philadelphia, 1950). Call no.: 507.73 P38mm [no.2].
Mason, John Alden, The Languages of South American Indians (Washington, 1950). Call no.: 572.061 Sm6b.
General note
10378.744 H26ola (on shelf)
Ixca texts: taken in Sierra Nevada de Santa Marta, Colombia 1924(?) (these are inserted in:Harvard University Directory 1910)
(in stacks)
SEE NEXT PAGE
Related Archival Materials note
Mason appears as a correspondent in the papers of Franz Boas (B B61), A. Irving Hallowell (Ms. Coll. 26), Elsie Clews Parsons (Ms. Coll. 29), and Charles B. Davenport (B D27).
The correspondence in the Boas Papers is particularly extensive (20 folders) and revealing of his work prior to 1920. In that year, he and Boas had a falling out over political matters, and between 1920 an 1927, they apparently did not exchange correspondence. Mason's later correspondence with Boas provides interesting details on the problems faced by the University Museum during the Depression.
The Benjamin Lee Whorf Papers at Yale contain some correspondence with Mason.
Separated Materials note
Transferred to the Printed Materials Department: Bascom, Burton William, Jr., Proto-Tepiman (Tepehuan-Piman), (Diss., University of Washington, 1965).
Sound recordings have been transferred for storage with the Audiovisual collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of John Alden Mason, 1967; the Mason estate, 1968; and Anthony Wallace, 1972 (accession numbers 1967-2584ms, 1968-1463ms, 1972-1311ms).
Scope and Contents note
The product of fifty years of research in the languages and cultures of Indians of the American southwest and Mexico, the John Alden Mason Papers are a diverse collection. The collection includes a thorough run of Mason's professional correspondence from the late 1920s until his retirement in 1958, with some correspondence from earlier and later periods, as well as field notes, photographs, and audio recordings.
The focus of much of Mason's linguistic research after 1916 was on the Sonoran (Uto-Aztecan) languages of northern Mexico and the southwestern United States, including Pima, Papago, Pima Bajo, Northern and Southern Tepehuan, Tepecano, and Yaqui, and the collection contains texts, lingusitic notes, and correspondence relating to each. Literate and engaging, Mason's letters from the field are particularly valuable for providing an insight into his perspective on field research, but also on the cultural, economic, and social conditions of the time.
Including both incoming letters and retained copies of outgoing, Mason's correspondence with Franz Boas, Alfred Kroeber, and Edward Sapir is particularly useful, and his most voluminous correspondent, Linton Satterthwaite, provides outstanding descriptions of his fieldwork in Mayan archaeology in southern Mexico and Guatemala during the 1930s. His even more voluminous files from the late 1940s while editor of American Anthropologist relate primarily to articles submitted to the journal and peer reviews.
Series I. Correspondence 1926-1967 20 linear feet
Series II. Latin American Institute for Race and Culture Studies 1921, 1934-1936 0.5 linear feet
Series III. Linguistics 1935-1956 2 linear feet
Series IV. Card Files and Notebooks 1911-1951 3 linear feet
Series V. Class notes 1904-1910 0.5 linear feet
Series VI. Photographs 1913-1951 1 linear foot
Series VII. Audio recordings 1948-1958 12 tapes
Biographical/Historical note
The archaeologist John Alden Mason was Curator of the University Museum at the University of Pennsylvania from 1926 until 1955. His research centered on the languages and cultures of the Indians of the American southwest and Mexico, including the Pima Bajo, Pima, Papago, Northern and Southern Tepehuan, and Tepecano.
Born at Orland, Indiana, on Nov 16, 1887, Mason was a naturalized Philadelphian. A graduate of Central High School, he received his bachelors degree at the University of Pennsylvania in 1907, and after being beated out by Frank Speck for a Harrison Fellowship, took a position as photographer to Prof. George Byron Gordon as a means of earning money to further his education. During the next two years, Mason took classes under Speck and Edward Sapir (who arrived at Penn in 1908), and spent the field season of 1909 with Sapir working on Uintah Ute linguistics and culture. His industry paid off, and in 1910, he won a scholarship to complete doctoral studies at the University of California, where, under the direction of Alfred Kroeber, he completed a dissretation on the ethnography and languages of the Indians of central California. His dissertation resulted in his first monograph, The Ethnology of the Salinan Indians (Berkeley: Univ. of Calif., 1912), which was quickly followed by a monograph on the Mutsun dialect of Coastanoan, and later by The Language of the Salinan Indians (Berkeley: Univ. of Calif., 1918).
Even while studying for his doctorate, however, the horizons of Mason's research began to expand beyond California to include the languages and cultures of the southwestern states and Mexico. He undertook his first major expedition after receiving his degree to Jalisco, Mexico, where, with the encouragement of Franz Boas, he conducted research on the Tepecano Indians in 1911 and 1912, hoping to produce a grammar of the language and to study Tepecano religion. Despite Boas' support, however, Mason was unable to land an academic job. Boas and Sapir arranged for Mason to continue productively, undertaking an expedition to the Great Slave Lake in 1913, and to Puerto Rico in 1914-1915 to research folklore and physical anthropology.
After subsisting on grant funds and fellowship support from his old department at Berkeley, Mason landed his first professional appointment as assistant curator of Mexican and South American Anthropology at the Field Museum of Natural History (1916-1923), after which he became assistant curator of Mexican and Central American Archaeology at the American Museum of Natural History, 1924-1925. Despite the demands of his curatorial duties, Mason initiated several important new projects, taking part in the Field Museum's archaeological expedition to Santa Marta, Columbia,in 1922-1923, and in 1918, initiating what would become many years of research on the Pima and Papago languages (the northern relatives of Tepecano and Tepehuan). Intending his research as part of a broader study of Uto-Aztecan languages, Mason worked closely with Juan Dolores, Ruth Underhill, and others well into the 1950s.
In 1926, Mason returned to Philadelphia to become Curator at the University Museum of the University of Pennsylvania, and despite the hardships of the Depression years, continued to expand his circle of interests--linguistic, ethnographic, and archaeological. Having taken an increasing interest in Meso-American and South American archaeology since his discovery of an important archaeological site in Puerto Rico, Mason's most productive research during the late 1920s until his retirement centered on Mayan archaeology (including work at Chichen Itza, Uxmal, and Palenque). He also worked on Aztec and Incan materials.
During his career, Mason published regularly in journals including The Museum Journal, Journal of American Folklore, International Journal of American Linguistics, and the American Anthropologist, of which was editor from 1945 through 1948. A fellow and vice president of the American Anthropological Assocation (1944) and president of the Society of American Archaeologists (1944), Mason retired from the University Museum in 1958, but remained active for several years thereafter as field advisor to the New World Archeology Foundation.
Mason married Florence Roberts on December 23, 1921 in Chicago, Illinois. The couple had one son and one daughter. Mason died in 1967 at the Bryn Mawr hospital, aged 82.
Physiology, Biochemistry, and Biophysics Note
Scholars of physiology, biochemistry, or biophysics may find the following of interest:
Lillie, Frank Rattray, 1870-1947 Correspondence (2 items) 1939 English
Agogino, George; American Anthropological Association--Publishing; American Anthropological Association.; Bascom, Burton W.; Benedict, Ruth, 1887-1848; Birge-Smith, Kaj, 1893-; Black, Fred L; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942; Brugge, David M.; Butler, Mary; Cadzow, Donald S.; Carpenter, Edmund, 1922-2011; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944; Cole, Fay-Cooper, 1881-1961; Cross, Dorothy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Dolores, Juan; Eggan, Fred, 1906-1991; Fejos, Paul, 1897-1963; Gamio, Manuel, 1883-1960; Greywacz, Kathryn B.; Harrington, John Peabody; Herskovits, Melville J., (Melville Jean), 1895-1963; Hodge, Frederick Webb, 1864-1956; Judd, Neil Merton, 1887-1976; Kelly, David H.; Kidder, Alfred Vincent, 1885-1963; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960; Latin-American Institute for Race and Culture Studies; Madeira, Percey Child, Jr.; Malinowski, Bronislaw, 1884-1942; Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978; Morley, Sylvanus Griswold, 1883-1948; Nuttall, Zelia, -- 1858-1933.; Radin, Paul, 1883-1959; Redfield, Robert, 1897-1958; Reichard, Gladys Amanda, 1893-1955; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939; Satterthwaite, Linton, 1897-; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967; Tozzer, Alfred M. -- (Alfred Marston), -- 1877-1954.; University of Pennsylvania. University Museum; University of Pennsylvania.; Vaillant, George Clapp, 1901-1945; Whorf, Benjamin Lee, 1897-1941; Wissler, Clark, 1870-1947; American Anthropologist; Anthropology--Societies, etc.; Archaeology; Bororo language (Brazil); Chihuahua (Chihuahua, Mexico); Diagrams.; Durango (Mexico); Egyptology.; Ethnology; Ge language; Gelatin silver prints; Indians of Mexico; Indians of Mexico--Languages; Indians of North America--Languages; Indians of North America--Southwest, New; Indians of North America--Southwest, New--Antiquities; Indians of South America--Languages; Jalisco (Mexico); Linguistics; Malali language; Maps.; Mayas--Antiquities; Mexico--Antiquities; Negatives; Palenque (Chiapas, Mexico); Photoprints; Phrenology; Pima Bajo language; Pima Indians; Pima language; Piman Indians; Piman languages; Quechua language; Recordings; Sketches.; Sonora (Mexico: State); Southwest Indians; Symbols; Tepecano Indians; Tepehuan language; Tohono O'Odham dialect; Tohono O'Odham Indians; Uto-Aztecan languages; Yaqui Indians
- Series I. Correspondence, 1926-1967; 20 linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Mason's extensive correspondence covers all aspects of his life, from reports on his fieldwork to answering casual questions referred to him through the University of Pennsylvania Museum, where he was a curator from 1926 to 1955. Included in this series is a consdierable quantity of material relating to the American Anthropological Association and the American Anthropologist (1928-1964).
  Among the many correspondents are George Agogino, Ruth Benedict, Kaj Birket-Smith, Fred L. Black, Franz Boas,Mary Butler, Donald S. Cadzow, Edmund S. Carpenter, J. McKeen Cattell, Fay-Cooper Cole, Dorothy Cross, Frederica de Laguna, Fred Eggan, Paul Fejos, Manuel Gamio, Kathryn B. Greywacz, Melville Herskovits, Frederick W. Hodge, Neil M. Judd, Alfred V. Kidder, Alfred L. Kroeber, Percey C. Madeira, Jr., Bronislaw Malinowski, Margaret Mead, Sylvanus G. Morley, Zelia Nuttall, Paul Radin, Froelich G. Rainey, Robert Redfield, Gladys A. Reichard, Linton Satterthwaite, Morris Swadesh, Alfred M. Tozzer, George C. Vaillant, and Clark Wissler.
  - Aach, Doris (Box 1)
  - Abarca, Soledad (Box 1)
  - Abbot, C. G (Box 1)
  - Aberle, David F (Box 1)
  - Abrahams, Harold J (Box 1)
  - Academia de la Lengua Maya (Box 1)
  - Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia (Box 1)
    - Cadwalader, Charles M B (Box 1)
    - Pennell, F W (Box 1)
    - Richards, Horace G (Box 1)
  - Acta Americana (Box 1)
    - Beals, Ralph (Box 1)
  - Adam, Leonard (Box 1)
  - Adams, Anna K (Box 1)
  - Adams, John C. L (Box 1)
  - Adams, Richard E (Box 1)
  - Address at linguistics symposium, AAA, Dec. 1931. (Box 1)
  - Adler, Adam W (Box 1)
  - Adney, Edwin Tappan (Box 1)
  - Adolph, H. J (Box 1)
  - Adolph, Henry (Box 1)
  - Adrianzén, Javier II (Box 1)
  - Adshade, Frank (Box 1)
  - Aduana de Panama (Box 1)
  - Age of man in America (Box 1)
  - Agencia Editora Mexicana (Box 1)
    - Chavez, Agustin Velazquez (Box 1)
  - Agogino, George (Box 1)
    - Bye, Carl R (Box 1)
    - [Compton], Carl (Box 1)
    - Fine, Jacob (Box 1)
    - Greywacz, Kathryn B (Box 1)
    - Kennedy, George C (Box 1)
    - Kimes, Margaret R (Box 1)
    - Krogman, W M (Box 1)
    - Oberly, H S (Box 1)
    - Rainey, Froelich G (Box 1)
    - Randolph, Norman (Box 1)
    - Reiter, Paul (Box 1)
    - Shapley, Harlow (Box 1)
    - Turner, Arthur C (Box 1)
    - Wormington, H M (Box 1)
  - Agogino, Mrs. Beulah (Box 1)
  - Aguilar P., Carlos H (Box 1)
  - Aguirra Benavides, Gustavo (Box 1)
  - Aguirry, P (Box 1)
  - Aiello, Lucy (Box 1)
  - Aitken, Robert T (Box 1)
  - Akron Art Institute (Box 1)
  - Alcala, Manuel (Box 1)
  - Alcover, D Vincente Castaneda (Box 1)
  - Alden, John (Box 1)
  - Aldrich, Charles R (Box 1)
  - Aldrich, Mrs. Herbert E (Box 1)
  - Aldridge, Curtice M (Box 1)
  - Alegria, Ricardo E (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Jack (Box 1)
  - Alexander, L. T (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Richard (Box 1)
  - Alfaro, Colon Elroy (Box 1)
  - Algier, Melvin (Box 1)
    - Rainey, Froelich G (Box 1)
  - Allen, E. S (Box 1)
  - Allen, Frederick W (Box 1)
  - Allen, Thomas J (Box 1)
  - Allott, Irvin W (Box 1)
  - Altman, Ralph C (Box 1)
  - Alvarez Conde J (Box 1)
  - Alvarez, Walter C (Box 1)
  - Amana, J (Box 1)
  - American Anthropologist (Box 1)
    - Abbott's Farm (Box 1)
    - Aberle, Sophie D (Box 1)
    - Ackerknecht, Erwin H (Box 1)
    - Adams, Leonhard (Box 1)
    - Aginsky, Burt W (Box 1)
    - Aginsky, Ethel G (Box 1)
    - Albrecht, Andrew C (Box 1)
    - American Book Center for War Devastated Libraries (Box 1)
    - American Russian Institute (Box 1)
    - Anderson, C H (Box 1)
    - Angel, J Lawrence (Box 1)
    - Antevs, Ernst (Box 1)
    - Arensberg, Conrad M (Box 1)
    - Argoe, Kostis T (Box 1)
    - Armattoe, R E G (Box 1)
    - Armstrong, Robert G (Box 1)
    - Arnold-Howard Publishing Company (Box 1)
    - Aronica, Rosemarie (Box 1)
    - Astrov, Margot (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Elizabeth (Box 1)
    - Baldus, Herbert (Box 1)
    - Banta Publishing Company (Box 2)
    - Barbeau, Marius (Box 2)
    - Barnes, Alped S (Box 2)
    - Barnett, H E (Box 2)
    - Barnett, H G (Box 2)
    - Barnitz, Eric (Box 2)
    - Barton, R F (Box 2)
    - Barton, R Paul (Box 2)
    - Bascom, William R (Box 2)
    - Bates, Elizabeth A (Box 2)
    - Beals, Ralph L (Box 2)
    - Beloit College Libraries (Box 2)
    - Bender, Ernest (Box 2)
    - Benedict, Ruth (Box 2)
    - Bennett, John W (Box 2)
    - Bennett, Wendell C (Box 2)
    - Berndt, Ronald M. and Catherine H (Box 2)
    - Bidney, David (Box 2)
    - Bird, Junius (Box 2)
    - Black, Glenn A (Box 2)
    - Blair, William C (Box 2)
    - Bloom, Leonard (Box 2)
    - Bodde, Derk (Box 2)
    - Bogos, Camille A (Box 2)
    - Bossard, James H S (Box 2)
    - Bowe and Bowes (Box 2)
    - Bowker, R R (Box 2)
    - Bowles, Gordon T (Box 2)
    - Brand, Donald D (Box 2)
    - Branin, Janet (Box 2)
    - Brant, Charles S (Box 2)
    - Braumüller, Wilhelm (Box 2)
    - Bretnall, G H (Box 2)
    - Brew, J O (Box 2)
    - Brewster, Paul G (Box 2)
    - Brill, E J (Box 2)
    - British Archaeology - Council (Box 2)
    - Bronson, Earle A (Box 2)
    - Brown, Ina Corinne (Box 2)
    - Brown, Norman (Box 2)
    - Bruner, Edward (Box 2)
    - Burford, C C (Box 2)
    - Burke, John (Box 2)
    - Buswell, James O III (Box 2)
    - Byers, Douglas S (Box 2)
    - Cappannari, Stephen C (Box 2)
    - Carlquist, G (Box 2)
    - Carnegie Institution of Wash (Box 2)
    - Caro, Julio (Box 2)
    - Carriere, J W (Box 2)
    - Carse, Mrs. Henry H (Box 2)
    - Carter, George F (Box 2)
    - Casagrande, Joseph B (Box 2)
    - Castells, J Martínez (Box 2)
    - Castro, Rodolfo Barón (Box 2)
    - Cejp, Karel (Box 2)
    - Ceough, Richard (Box 2)
    - Chandler, Mary (Box 2)
    - Chaplin, Ruth A (Box 2)
    - Chapp, Robert (Box 2)
    - Chapple, Eliot D (Box 2)
    - Clack, Jane (Box 2)
    - Coelho, Julio C Neves (Box 2)
    - Cohen, Albert K (Box 2)
    - Colbert, Edwin H (Box 2)
    - Cole, Fay-Cooper (Box 2)
    - Coleman, D C (Box 2)
    - Collier, Donald (Box 2)
    - Collier, Malcolm C (Box 2)
    - Collins, Henry B., Jr (Box 2)
    - Columbia University Press (Box 2)
    - Comas, Juan (Box 2)
    - Cooper, John M (Box 2)
    - Copeland, D Graham (Box 2)
    - Count, Earl W (Box 2)
    - Count, Earl W (Box 2)
    - Crespillo, Alberto (Box 2)
    - Crosby, Henry Lemar (Box 2)
    - da Costa Eduardo, Octavio (Box 2)
    - Dale, Gilbert R (Box 2)
    - Daniel, John F (Box 2)
    - Datta-Majunder, Nabendu (Box 2)
    - Davidson, D S (Box 2)
    - Davis, A K (Box 2)
    - Davis, Kingsley (Box 2)
    - Day, A Grove (Box 2)
    - De Laguna, Mrs. Frederica (Box 2)
    - Denhard, Pfeifer (Box 2)
    - Densmore, Frances (Box 2)
    - Devereux, George (Box 2)
    - Dexter, Lewis A (Box 2)
    - Dockstader, Frederick J (Box 2)
    - Dodge, Ernest S (Box 2)
    - Donath, Mrs. Dorothy (Box 2)
    - Drew, Robin A (Box 2)
    - Duboc, Jessie L (Box 2)
    - Duke University (Box 2)
    - Echolm, Gordon (Box 3)
    - Edinburgh, University of (Box 3)
    - Eggan, Fred (Box 3)
    - Eiseley, Loren C (Box 3)
    - Ellwood, Charles A (Box 3)
    - Elmendorf, William W (Box 3)
    - Elwin, V E (Box 3)
    - Embree, John F (Box 3)
    - Emory, Kenneth P (Box 3)
    - Encyclopaedia of the Soviet Union (Box 3)
    - Evans-Pritchard, E E (Box 3)
    - Ewers, John C (Box 3)
    - Faber and Faber, Publishers (Box 3)
    - Fanshawe, D B (Box 3)
    - Farquahr, Samuel T (Box 3)
    - Fauset, Arthur Huff (Box 3)
    - Faye, Paul Louis (Box 3)
    - Feingold, Jessica (Box 3)
    - Fejos, Paul (Box 3)
    - Fenton, William N (Box 3)
    - Ferguson, Mrs. Alice L L (Box 3)
    - Field, Henry (Box 3)
    - Fisher, Addison W (Box 3)
    - Fisher, Lloyd (Box 3)
    - Flannery, Regina (Box 3)
    - Forde, Daryll (Box 3)
    - Fortune, R F (Box 3)
    - Fox, Mrs. Dorothy Gregg (Box 3)
    - Franco, Mariano (Box 3)
    - Freeman, J. D (Box 3)
    - Furer-Haimendorf, C. von (Box 3)
    - Gaertner, J A (Box 3)
    - Gamio, Manuel (Box 3)
    - Gard, Richard (Box 3)
    - Garfield, Viola E (Box 3)
    - Garth, Thomas R (Box 3)
    - Gayton, A Helen (Box 3)
    - Ghisletti, Louis V (Box 3)
    - Gibson, Charles, II (Box 3)
    - Gibson, Gordon D (Box 3)
    - Gierse, Z Alexander (Box 3)
    - Gifford, E W (Box 3)
    - Gilbert,William H (Box 3)
    - Gillette, J M (Box 3)
    - Gilliam, Charles Edgar (Box 3)
    - Gillin, John (Box 3)
    - Gini, Corrando (Box 3)
    - Gjessing, Gustorm (Box 3)
    - Gladwin, Harold (Box 3)
    - Gladwin, Thomas (Box 3)
    - Gluckman, Max (Box 3)
    - Goldfrank, Esther S (Box 3)
    - Goldschmidt, W R (Box 3)
    - Goodman, Mrs. Mary Ellen (Box 3)
    - Gordon, Maxine M (Box 3)
    - Graham, David G (Box 3)
    - Graubard, Mark (Box 3)
    - Greenberg, Joseph H (Box 3)
    - Greenman, E F (Box 3)
    - Gregory, William K (Box 3)
    - Griffin, John W (Box 3)
    - Grodsky, Mrs. Maya R (Box 3)
    - Groot, Gerard (Box 3)
    - Gunda, Béla (Box 3)
    - Gunnell, Francis (Box 3)
    - Gurney, Mrs. Natalie (Box 3)
    - Gusakoff, M (Box 3)
    - Gussow, Zachary (Box 3)
    - Guthe, Carl E (Box 3)
    - Guthiérra Vera, Roberto O (Box 3)
    - Hadlock, Wendell S (Box 3)
    - Hall, Robert A., Jr (Box 3)
    - Hallowell, A Irving (Box 3)
    - Halpert, Herbert (Box 3)
    - Hambly, Wilfred D (Box 3)
    - Haring, Douglas G (Box 3)
    - Harper and Brothers (Box 3)
    - Harrington, John P (Box 3)
    - Harrington, M R (Box 3)
    - Harris, Jack (Box 3)
    - Harris, Zelig S (Box 3)
    - Harrison, Mrs. W H (Box 3)
    - Hartman, Mrs. Helen B (Box 3)
    - Hartung, Frank E (Box 3)
    - Hassrick, Royal B (Box 3)
    - Haury, Emil W (Box 3)
    - Hause, Helen E (Box 3)
    - Hawley, Florence (Box 3)
    - Hawthorn,Harry (Box 3)
    - Heine-Geldern, Robert (Box 3)
    - Heitzner, Bella (Box 3)
    - Hencken, H O'Neill (Box 3)
    - Henry, Jules (Box 3)
    - Herskovits, Melville J (Box 3)
    - Herzog, George (Box 3)
    - Hewes, Gordon W (Box 3)
    - Heyer, Virginia (Box 3)
    - Heyneman, Doris (Box 3)
    - Highland, Genevieve A (Box 3)
    - Hilger, Mary Inez (Box 3)
    - Hill, W W (Box 3)
    - Hodge, F W (Box 3)
    - Hoebel, E Adamson (Box 4)
    - Hoeg, Erik (Box 4)
    - Hoijer, Harry (Box 4)
    - Holden, W C (Box 4)
    - Honigmann, Irma (Box 4)
    - Honigmann, John J (Box 4)
    - Honigsheim, Paul (Box 4)
    - Hooten, Earnest A (Box 4)
    - Houghton, Frederick (Box 4)
    - House, James (Box 4)
    - Howells, W W (Box 4)
    - Hsin, L. N (Box 4)
    - Hulse, Frederick S (Box 4)
    - Human Relations (Box 4)
    - Hurst, C. T (Box 4)
    - Ironica, Rosemarie (Box 4)
    - Irwin, Dorothy V (Box 4)
    - Ives, Ronald L (Box 4)
    - Izikowitz, Karl Gustav (Box 4)
    - Jacobs, Melville (Box 4)
    - Jacobsen, Thorkild (Box 4)
    - Jansson, L (Box 4)
    - Jeffries, M D W (Box 4)
    - Jennings, Jesse D (Box 4)